Fluid animations are an essential part of building any native application.
流畅的动画效果是构建原生应用的基本组成部分
Because of that, React Native comes with an animated library baked into it.
因此 React Native 内置了动画库
It's not surprisingly called animated.
名字就叫做 Animated
The goal of Animated is to convey physical,
Animated 的目标是
believable motion in your UI.
在用户界面上展现逼真的物理动作
Animated focuses on declarative relationships between
Animated 侧重于在输入和输出之间
inputs and outputs with configurable transforms in between.
建立声明式关系 并且二者之间的转换可以配置
Let's take a look at an example.
我们来看一个示例
This video is going to be a fun one because we are going to play
这个视频内容将很有趣
around with React Native's Animated Library.
因为我们将使用 React Native 的 Animated 库
Animated, as you can probably imagine is for doing animations inside a React Native App.
顾名思义 Animated 就是在 React Native 应用中实现动画效果
So here, what we have is our component and all we're doing is we have a container,
这是我们的组件 里面有容器
and then we are rendering an image.
并且渲染一个图片
So what that looks like on iOS and Android is just this right here.
这就是在 iOS 和 Android 上的效果
So, there are really three types of animations that we can do,
我们可以利用 Animated
three main types of animations we can do with Animated.
实现三种主要的动画效果
Decay, which is going to have an initial velocity,
Decay 以一个初始速度开始
and then it's going to slow to a stop.
并逐渐减慢停止
Spring, which is going to kind of be like a Spring in physics as you've seen before.
Spring 就像你之前见过的物理弹簧效果
And then Timing, which is just going to animate a value over time.
然后是 Timing 在一定的时间范围内表示值的渐变动画效果
So what we're going to do is,
我们要做的是...
I want to go ahead and,
转到这里
when our component mounts,
当组件加载时
we are going to animate our image component.
我们将使图片组件出现动画效果
So the very first thing that you need to realize with
对于动画
animations is essentially what you're doing,
首先要了解的是
is just like you would with any property.
就像任何属性一样
We're going to set a property on our state,
我们将在状态上设置一个属性
and then animate it,
然后 Animated
it's going to go and change the property on
将更改状态上的这一属性
our state which will then animate the component.
使组件具有动画效果
Now, that's a little high level,
内容有点深奥
so let's go ahead and take a look at what this looks like.
我们看看具体流程
So here we are sticking an opacity property on our state,
我们在这里向状态上添加了一个 opacity 属性
because what I want to do,
因为我要做的是
is when the component mounts,
当组件加载时
I want to slowly fade the image in,
我想缓慢地显示该图片
or slowly take the opacity from zero all the way to one.
也就是让透明度缓慢地从 0 变成 1
So what we'll do is we will say,
我们在这里输入
opacity is going to be a new animated value,
opacity: new Animated Value()
and it's going to have a default value at zero.
默认值为 0
So we're going to start the opacity at zero.
使 opacity 从 0 开始
Now, what we need to do,
现在我们需要
is we need to make sure that we add this opacity as a style on our image.
确保将此 opacity 当做样式添加到图片上
But you can't just use an ordinary image,
但是不能使用普通图片
we need to go ahead and say, Animated.Image.
需要输入 Animated.Image
And now, instead of having just a width and height,
现在不仅只有 width 和 height
what we're also going to do,
我们还将转到这里
is we're going to come in here and say,
输入 opacity
opacity which we are going to grab up here from our state.
我们将在这里从我们的状态上获取 opacity
But as you can probably guess,
但是你可能猜到了
if we were to run this right now,
如果现在运行应用的话
you'll notice what would happen is,
你会发现
we don't have any image anymore.
没有任何图片
That's because we've set the image value to zero right here.
这是因为我们在这里将图片值设为了 0
And then what we're doing,
然后
is we added that opacity value to our image.
我们将该 opacity 值添加到图片上
So as of right now,
所以现在
our image just has an opacity of zero,
图片的 opacity 为 0
but what we actually want to do is animate that when the component mounts as I mentioned.
但是我们希望当组件加载时 实现动画效果
So the way we can do that,
我们在这里
is we can say, componentDidMount,
输入 componentDidMount
and when this component mounts,
当该组件加载时
first let's grab the opacity off of these states.
首先从状态上获取 opacity
And now, using Animated's timing method,
然后使用 Animated 的 timing 方法
what I want to do is animate the opacity from zero to one,
我希望将 opacity 从 0 过渡到 1
taking one whole second.
持续时间为 1 秒
So the way we will do that,
实现方法是
is we will say,
在这里输入
Animated.timing and invoke it.
Animated.timing 调用该方法
And then the first thing we pass it is the actual value that we want to modify.
首先要传入的是我们希望修改的实际值
So we want to modify our opacity.
我们想修改 opacity
And then, we pass it an object which has some options on it.
然后传入一个具有一些选项的对象
So we will say, we want to modify opacity to a value of one.
我们想将 opacity 修改为值 1
So we're going to go from zero to one,
我们将从 0 变成 1
and it's going to take 1,000 milliseconds.
持续时间为 1,000 毫秒
And then, you need to always be sure to run.start,
始终记得要运行 .start
to start the animation.
以便启动动画
So now, what should happen if everything's working?
现在如果一切正常的话 会发生什么？
You'll notice when our app runs,
如果应用运行的话
what happens is we get that nice little fade and effect, and it looks great.
出现了不错的淡入效果 看起来很棒
But now, what I want to do is, I actually want to,
但是现在
instead of just having a fade in,
我不再希望是淡入效果
I want to start it out from a width and height of zero,
而是从宽和高都为 0 开始
and bring it all the way up to the width that it currently is.
然后变成当前的宽度
So what we'll do for that,
为此
is we will use Animated's Spring property.
我们将使用 Animated 的 Spring 属性
So let's add a few more properties to our states.
我们向状态添加几个属性
We will say, width is going to start at zero as well.
width 也从 0 开始
And then height is going to also be an animated value that starts out at zero.
height 也为 Animated.Value 并从 0 开始
And then, let's go ahead and just as we did with opacity, we'll say,
然后就像对待 opacity 一样
width and height, and then we will add these as properties here.
在这里输入 width 和 height 并且在这里添加这些属性
So if I save and look at this,
保存下代码 看看效果
what we will see is nothing.
什么也没看到
Because right now, the images have a width and the height of zero.
因为现在图片的宽和高是 0
So just as I did up here,
就像这里一样
I also want to animate those from zero to a specific value, specifically, 300.
我还希望将这些从 0 变为特定的值 300
So what we'll do is we will say, Animated.spring.
输入 Animated.spring
Let's do the width first.
首先设置 width
So we want to modify the width.
我们想要修改 width
Now, we want to take it from a value of zero to 300.
现在我们希望值从 0 变成 300
And instead of duration,
这里不再是 duration
because we aren't using timing, we're using spring.
因为我们使用的是 spring 而不是 timing
What we'll do, is we will give it a speed of five.
将 speed 设为 5
This defaults to a speed of 12.
默认地 speed 为 12
So a speed of five is a little bit slower.
speed 为 5 稍微慢些
And then we will call.start.
然后调用 .start
And now, we're going to do that exact same thing but with the height.
复制这段代码 但是改为 height
Now if everything is working, what we should see.
如果一切正常的话 我们应该能看到...
And it is not working.
出现问题了
That's because we need to grab width and height right here.
因为我们需要在这里获取 width 和 height
Now if everything is working,
现在如果一切正常的话
you'll notice that not only does the image opacity go from zero to one,
不仅图片的透明度从 0 变成 1
but the image is also going from a width and height of zero all the way to 300.
而且宽和高也从 0 变成了 300